Guide to the John C. Becher Soldier Show collection, 1940-1953
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
John C. Becher Soldier Show collection
1940-1953
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
John C. Becher
C0090
9 linear feet (17 boxes)
The John C. Becher Soldier Show collection contains entertainment materials written by and for the United States military during and immediately following World War II. The collection is arranged by material type and entertainment themes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by John C. Becher in 1979 through Harold Arburg, Director of Arts and Humanities, U.S. Office of Education.
Historical Information
Keeping morale high was important during the war. This was recognized at the highest military levels. General George C. Marshall, Chief of Staff, for example, stressed the importance of maintaining high morale: "Napoleon evaluated morale over material as three to one. I believe that recent experiences indicate a re-estimate of this value - the odds being near five to one, or probably even ten to one in some instances in favor of the psychological factor" (Morale Program, box 7 folder 2 page 7). Programs and services that maintained or heightened morale covered a wide range - athletics, libraries, religion, education - and none was more important than entertainment, which is well-represented by the materials in the Becher Collection.
Entertaining troops during World War II was an enormous enterprise. The celebrated USO-Camp Shows was a civilian-based organization that provided professional entertainment for the Armed Forces. The U.S. Army Motion Picture Service was a non-profit organization that sponsored movie theaters to ease the transition from civilian to military life. A related group, the U.S.O. Mobile Motion Picture Service, showed films to overseas troops. Whereas these organizations provided passive forms of entertainment, the Entertainment Section of the Army Special Services Division took a different approach. They actually included the soldiers in creating their own entertainment. These were called Soldier Shows.
Soldier Shows were made by soldiers for soldiers. The principal objective was to achieve mass participation. A wide range of talent was employed in creating Soldier Shows - including singers, dancers, actors, orators, trivia buffs, costume and scenery makers, artists, and carpenters. Because mass participation by military personnel was encouraged, the program had a virtually unlimited field to draw on.
Soldiers participating in Soldier Shows acted in skits and plays, sang musical numbers, performed comedy routines, quizzed other soldiers, and made arts and crafts. Such activities forged common bonds among the troops and provided emotional links to their homeland. Soldier Shows were particularly effective in boosting the morale of hospitalized soldiers. The therapeutic value of Soldier Shows played an important role in the physical and mental rehabilitation of injured soldiers.
Soldier Shows were remarkably effective in boosting morale. In fact, reports have shown that the program was one of the easiest and most effective ways to combat low morale. (Morale Program, box 1 folder 2 page 7). General Dwight D. Eisenhower, in a back-stage visit to the cast who put on a Soldier Show in North Africa, praised their usefulness in the war effort: "You are entertaining soldiers. You are not fighting with guns - but your job is just as important. As long as you are doing your job well... you will be rendering a service, and a great one, to your fellow soldiers and your country" (Morale Program, box 1 folder 2 page 7).
Scope and Content
The John C. Becher Soldier Show collection contains entertainment materials written by and for the United States military during and immediately following World War II. The collection is arranged by material type and entertainment themes. The six cubic feet (nine linear feet) cover the years 1940 through 1953.
Most of the items in the collection are Soldier Shows, entertainments written to amuse overseas troops and to boost morale. Produced by the Army Special Services Division, the scripts were written by professional and amateur playwrights. Many were created by military personnel attending the Special Services School in Lexington, Virginia (1943-1946). The collection also includes: newspaper and magazine clippings, war humor, poems, blackouts, quizzes, crafts manuals, original songs, song parodies, sheet music, flyers, pamphlets, theatrical manuals and guides, lesson plans and lectures, production ideas, and comedy routines. There are also several military-issued Pocket Guides to foreign lands, including guides to Burma, Germany, Greece, West Africa, Italy, and Great Britain.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by item group, such as Soldier Shows, scripts, theatrical manuals, and pocket guides.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the, which contains documents, photographs, and memorabilia from his time in the Air Force during World War II.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
United States. Army Service Forces. Special Service Division.
Subjects:
Soldiers--Recreation--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Theater and the war.
Contents List
- John C. Becher Soldier Show collection
  - The Bells Are Ringing (Folder 1, Box 1)
    Script by unknown
  - The Captains and the Kings (Folder 2, Box 1)
    Script by Leo Lieberman
  - Conversations in the Dark (Folder 3, Box 1)
    Script by William Hanley
  - Dear Me, the Sky Is Falling (Folder 4, Box 1)
    Script by Leonard Spigelgass
  - Ding Dong Bell (Folder 5, Box 1)
    Script by Gurney Campbell and Daphne Athas
  - Ding Dong Bell (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Fifth from Garbaldi (The Man Who Made the Mountain Shake) (Folder 7, Box 1)
    Script by Paddy Chayefsky
  - The Heavenly Twins (Folder 8, Box 1)
    Script by Louis Kronenberger
  - I Giveth and Giveth (Folder 1, Box 2)
    Script by Phoebe Ephron and Henry Ephron
  - Jolly's Progress (Folder 2, Box 2)
    Script by Lonnie Coleman
  - Leaven of Malice (Folder 3, Box 2)
    Script by Robertson Davies
  - Libby (Dear Me, the Sky is Falling) (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - The Mackerel Plaza (Folder 5, Box 2)
    Script by William McCleery
  - A Majority of One (Folder 6, Box 2)
  - A Passage to India (Folder 7, Box 2)
    Script by Santha Rama Rau
  - Roots (Folder 1, Box 3)
    Script by Arnold Wesker
  - Seidman and Son (Folder 2, Box 3)
    Script by Elick Moll
  - Semi - Detached (Folder 3, Box 3)
    Script by Patricia Joudry
  - Sunrise at Campobello (Folder 4, Box 3)
    Script by Dore Schary
  - Third Best Sport (Folder 5, Box 3)
    Script by Michael Howard
  - The Tunnel of Love (Folder 6, Box 3)
    Script by Joseph Fields and Peter de Vries
  - The Unsinkable Mrs. Brown (Folder 7, Box 3)
    Script by Richard Morris
  - The Unsinkable Mrs. Brown (Folder 1, Box 3A)
  - The Unsinkable Molly Brown (Folder 2, Box 3A)
  - Venus at Large (Folder 3, Box 3A)
    Script by Henry Denker
  - A Way of Life (Folder 4, Box 3A)
    Script by Murray Schisgal
  - The Wayward Stork (Folder 5, Box 3A)
    Script by Harry Tugend
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. I 1943 (Folder 1, Box 4)
    "The Reluctant Draftee" and "Ten Minute Break": Two Complete Soldier Shows
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. VI 1943 (Folder 2, Box 4)
    Comedy Acts and Minstrel Show Material
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. VII 1943 (Folder 3, Box 4)
    Revue Sketches Vaudeville Comedy Acts
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. VIII 1943 (Folder 4, Box 4)
    "Take it or Leave It": A Humorous Quiz Book
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. IX 1943 (Folder 5, Box 4)
    Abbott and Costello, Burns and Allen, Fred Allen, Charlie McCarthy, Fibber McGee and Molly: Comedy Scenes
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. X 1943 (Folder 6, Box 4)
    Soldier Shows Guide
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XI 1943 (Folder 7, Box 4)
    The Army Play by Play: Five Prize-Winning One-Act Plays
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XII 1944 (Folder 8, Box 4)
    Blackouts and Sketches
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XV 1944 (Folder 9, Box 4)
    GI: Prize Winning Blackouts
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XVI 1944 (Folder 10, Box 4)
    G.I. Revues: 10 Package Shows
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XVII 1945 (Folder 11, Box 4)
    G.I. One Act Plays
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XVIII 1945 (Folder 12, Box 4)
    Chillers and Thrillers: A Book of Mystery Sketches
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XIX 1945 (Folder 13, Box 4)
    MC Jackpot
  - Soldier Shows, Vol. XX 1945 (Folder 14, Box 4)
    Skits and Bits
  - Hi Yank!: The Army Show (Folder 1, Box 5)
    Soldier Shows "Blueprint Special"
  - OK,USA: A Guide Book in Music and Comedy June 1945 (Folder 2, Box 5)
  - P.F.C. Mary Brown: A WAC Musical Revue (Folder 3, Box 5)
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 1 (Folder 1, Box 6)
    Blackouts, Sketches, Quizzes, Parodies, Games
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 2 (Folder 2, Box 6)
    Games, Puzzles, Quizzes
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 3 (Folder 3, Box 6)
    "Bedzapoppin", (A Revue), Games, Quizzes
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 4 (Folder 4, Box 6)
  - Soldier Shows: hospital Entertainment Guide No. 5 (Folder 5, Box 6)
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 6 June 1945 (Folder 6, Box 6)
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 7 October 1945 (Folder 7, Box 6)
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 8 December 1945 (Folder 8, Box 6)
  - Soldier Shows: Hospital Entertainment Guide No. 6 [No. 9] November 1945 (Folder 9, Box 6)
    "No. 6" is corrected by hand to "No. 9"
  - "At Ease," Vol. I 1942 (Folder 10, Box 6)
    Comedy Sketches
  - "At Ease," Vol. II 1942 (Folder 11, Box 6)
    Minstrel Shows with Music
  - "At Ease," Vol. III 1942 (Folder 12, Box 6)
    Music and Lyrics for Musical Comedies and Revues
  - "At Ease," Vol. IV 1943 (Folder 13, Box 6)
    Musical Opening Choruses, Finales and Production Numbers for Soldier Shows
  - "At Ease," Vol. XIII 1944 (Folder 14, Box 6)
    Time Out
  - Fourth Service Command Enlisted Men's Conference on Soldier Shows November 22-26, 1943 (Folder 1, Box 7)
    Held at Fort McPherson, Georgia
  - Fourth Service Command Morale Program April 25, 1944 (Folder 2, Box 7)
    Held at Atlanta, Georgia
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part I September 3 - October 14, 1944 (Folder 3, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part II October 15 - November 11, 1944 (Folder 4, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part III November 12 - December 9, 1944 (Folder 5, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part IV December 10, 1944 - January 6, 1945 (Folder 6, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part V January 7 - February 3, 1945 (Folder 7, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part VI February 4 - March 3, 1945 (Folder 8, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part VII March 1945 (Folder 9, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part VIII April 1945 (Folder 10, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part IX May 1945 (Folder 11, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part X June 1945 (Folder 12, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part XI July 1945 (Folder 13, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: 26 Weeks Entertainment Program for Service Commands, Part XII August 5 - September 1, 1945 (Folder 14, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows: Entertainment Guide No. 1 (Folder 15, Box 7)
    Reception Center: Blackouts, Parodies, Games
  - Soldier Shows: Entertainment Guide No. 2 (Folder 16, Box 7)
    Reception Center, Blackouts, Parodies, Revues
  - Soldier Handicrafts June 1945 (Folder 17, Box 7)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 18 (Folder 1, Box 8)
    Entertainment Section: Radio and Theatrical Material: Skits, Blackouts, Sketches
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 19 (Folder 2, Box 8)
    Radio and Theatrical Material: Skits, Blackouts, Sketches
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 20 (Folder 3, Box 8)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 21 (Folder 4, Box 8)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 22 (Folder 5, Box 8)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 23 (Folder 6, Box 8)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 24 (Folder 7, Box 8)
    It's the G.I. State Fair
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 24 (Folder 8, Box 8)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 25 (Folder 9, Box 8)
    Thanksgiving, Mock Election, Revues, Parodies, Blackouts, Radio Scripts, Crossovers
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 27 (Folder 10, Box 8)
    Murder Mystery, Production Numbers, Revues, Parodies, Blackouts, Radio Scripts, Crossovers
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 28 (Folder 11, Box 8)
    Broadway Special Featuring New York's latest Hit "The Hasty Heart," Revues, Parodies, Blackouts, Radio Scripts, Crossovers
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 29 (Folder 12, Box 8)
    Folio Highlights, Revues, Parodies, Blackouts, Radio Scripts, Crossovers
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 30 (Folder 13, Box 8)
    Entertainment Grab Bag, Revues, Parodies, Blackouts, Radio Scripts, Crossovers
  - Soldier Shows (Folder 14, Box 8)
    Sketches, Crossover, Quizzes, Revues, Blackouts, Parodies
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 6 (Folder 1, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 7 (Folder 2, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 8 (Folder 3, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 9 (Folder 4, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 10 (Folder 5, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 11 (Folder 6, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 12 (Folder 7, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 13 (Folder 8, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio no. 14 (Folder 9, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 15 (Folder 10, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 16 (Folder 11, Box 9)
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 17 (Folder 12, Box 9)
  - Lesson Plans for Special Services February 4, 1944 (Folder 1, Box 10)
    Schedules 1 - 14
  - Paper Craft for G.I. Shows (Folder 2, Box 10)
    Stage instructions and hand drawn costume and set images
  - Decorations for Christmas Entertainment October 6, 1943 (Folder 3, Box 10)
  - Fox Movietone News (Folder 4, Box 10)
    Music score
  - Literary Quotes (Folder 5, Box 10)
  - Parody on "The Little Brown Jug" (Folder 6, Box 10)
  - You Gave Me K.P. (Folder 7, Box 10)
    Parody on contemporary song
  - Through Channels: A Comedy in Too Many Acts 1942 (Folder 8, Box 10)
    Script by Barnett Shaw
  - Confessions of an ExOCS Man July 4, 1942 (Folder 9, Box 10)
    Story by Sidney P. Goldman
  - Confessions of an ExOCS Man July 4, 1942 (Folder 10, Box 10)
  - What to Do in Case of an Air Raid (Folder 11, Box 10)
    War humor
  - What to Do in Case of an Air Raid (Folder 12, Box 10)
  - Epitaph (Folder 13, Box 10)
    Poem by Shakespeare?
  - The Wolf (Folder 14, Box 10)
    Poem
  - How to Be a Success in the Army: Know Your Army Terms (Folder 15, Box 10)
  - Latest War Bulletin (Folder 16, Box 10)
  - Poem (Folder 17, Box 10)
  - Letter From Hornie [Homie?] V. (Folder 18, Box 10)
    "...army life and what the average soldier has to put up with."
  - "Selective Service Blues" and "The Soldiers Prayer, 1941" (Folder 19, Box 10)
    Poems
  - War Dictionary June 11 (Folder 20, Box 10)
    War humor by Herb Graffis
  - Nice Job if You Can Get It! (Folder 21, Box 10)
    Script
  - The Girl Friend Air Corps Model W O W (Folder 22, Box 10)
  - A Supply officer Tears Off a Hot Love Letter (Folder 23, Box 10)
    By Cpl. Adolph Abramson
  - So I Think I'm Stupid (Folder 24, Box 10)
    Article by Weare Holbrook
  - Navy Department: SPARS June 1, 1943 (Folder 25, Box 10)
  - Credo of Men at Arms October 1941 (Folder 26, Box 10)
    War humor by Robert T. Souter in Esquire, p. 65
  - Chow Hounds General Orders (Folder 27, Box 10)
  - The Doughboy's Dream February 27, 1943 (Folder 28, Box 10)
    Script by Ben Hecht in Collier's, pp. 11-13, 37-39
  - What's the Score? (Folder 29, Box 10)
    "A Soldier's Reminder of the War's Background, Its Purpose and Its Prospects"; Script by Sgt. Fred Stewart
  - The Drunkard (Folder 30, Box 10)
    "An old-fashioned melodrama in two acts"
  - Quiz Program September 23, 1944 (Folder 31, Box 10)
    "Used at SSMS"
  - Untitled April 18, 1944 (Folder 32, Box 10)
    Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS) broadcast; Script by Norman Corwin
  - Pie and Box Supper and Patriotic Mass Meeting - Flyer Feburary 9 (Folder 33, Box 10)
    Held at Fairview School Auditorium
  - The Moon is Down - Flyer October 25 (Folder 34, Box 10)
    John Steinbeck's play, presented by the Tulsa Little Theater Group in War Department, at Theater No. 2, Camp Crowder, Missouri
  - Technical Manual for WAAC, M1 September 11, 1942 (Folder 35, Box 10)
  - Curtain Going Up July 21, 1945 (Folder 1, Box 11)
    Blackouts, Crossovers and Parodies for WAC Variety Nights
  - Soldier Shows: Staging Area and Transport Entertainment Guide (Folder 2, Box 11)
    Blackouts, Sketches, Quizzes, Parodies and Games
  - Amateur Theatrical Manual 1941 (Folder 3, Box 11)
    Prepared by the National Theater Conference and the Morale Branch of the United States Army
  - Public Speaking 1942-1943 (Folder 4, Box 11)
    Speech Work Material by Doyle Virginia Cockrell, San Antonio Vocational and Technical High School
  - Soldier Theatricals: Proposed Guide (Folder 5, Box 11)
    "The attached suggestions are furnished for the purpose of assisting the Theatrical Technical Advisor in the many problems which arise in the producing, directing, rehearsing and presentation of soldier theatricals."
  - Soldier Theatricals: Bulletin V (Folder 6, Box 11)
    The Production Staff, Principles of Directing and Acting, Production of One-Act and Full-Length Plays
  - Scripts of Typical Soldier Shows (Folder 7, Box 11)
  - Production Ideas For a G.I. Variety Show (Folder 8, Box 11)
    Distributed by the Special Services Division, A.S.F.
  - Soldier Shows, Folio No. 2 (Folder 9, Box 11)
    Radio and Theatrical Material, Skits, Blackouts, Sketches
  - Entertainment Section, No. 8 (Folder 10, Box 11)
    Sixty-Second Blackouts
  - Entertainment Section, No. 12 (Folder 11, Box 11)
    Musical Quizzical
  - Soldier Show Pamphlet, Project #1 (Folder 12, Box 11)
    Fourth Service Command Soldier Show Conferences
  - Pattern for Fundamental All-Soldier Variety Show (#1), Project #2 (Folder 13, Box 11)
    Fourth Service Command Soldier Shows
  - Pattern for Fundamental All-Soldier Variety Show (#1), Project #2 (Folder 14, Box 11)
  - The Soldier Show Work Shop, Project #3 (Folder 15, Box 11)
  - Abbott and Costello Prison Routine, Script I (Folder 16, Box 11)
    "For the entertainment of the Armed Forces overseas"
  - Charlie McCarthy Circus Routine, Script II (Folder 17, Box 11)
  - Abbott and Costello Sea Spot, Script III (Folder 18, Box 11)
  - Abbott and Costello New Radio Station Routine, Script IV (Folder 19, Box 11)
  - Abbott and Costello Gymnasium Routine, Script V (Folder 20, Box 11)
  - Burlesque on Early Morning Program, Script VII (Folder 21, Box 11)
  - Abbott and Costello Second Spot - Court Routine, Script VIII (Folder 22, Box 11)
  - Burlesque of Radio Program #3, Script IX (Folder 23, Box 11)
  - Sketch Material for Camp Radio Show: Golf Lesson Routine, Script X (Folder 24, Box 11)
    Prepared by the Radio Section, Headquarters Branch Office
  - Abbott and Costello Substitute Comedy Routine, Script XI (Folder 25, Box 11)
  - Newspaper Routine #2, Script XII (Folder 26, Box 11)
  - Sketch Material for Camp Radio Show: Dude Ranch Routine, Script XIII (Folder 27, Box 11)
  - Abbott and Costello Robin Hood Sketch, Script XIV (Folder 28, Box 11)
  - Abbott and Costello Routing #1, Script XV (Folder 29, Box 11)
  - Minstrel Show #2, Script XVI (Folder 30, Box 11)
  - If Soldiers Selected Their Clothes as Women Do, Script XVII (Folder 31, Box 11)
    by Robert Riley Crutcher, presented by the Special Service Division of the War Department
  - Reveille Revue, Script XVIII (Folder 32, Box 11)
    presented by the Special Service Division of the War Department
  - Minstrel Show #1, Script XIX (Folder 33, Box 11)
    Presented by the Special Services Division of the War Department
  - A and R - Trocities (Folder 1, Box 12)
    Skit by Lt. W.P. Moore; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Airplane Skecth (Folder 2, Box 12)
    Skit; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - "Always on K.P." and "The First Hundred Years" (Folder 3, Box 12)
    Song parodies; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - "Always on K.P." and "The First Hundred Years" (Folder 4, Box 12)
  - An Order (Folder 5, Box 12)
  - The Army Made an Actor Out of Me (Folder 6, Box 12)
    Words and music by Sgt. J. C. Lewis; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - As the Movies See Us (Folder 7, Box 12)
    Skit by Cpl. Raymond Simon; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Ballet Invades the Drama (Folder 8, Box 12)
  - Barker's Spiel (Folder 9, Box 12)
  - Barker's Spiel (Folder 10, Box 12)
  - Blackouts (Folder 11, Box 12)
    Various skits; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Blackouts and Production Numbers (Folder 12, Box 12)
    Various skits and production numbers; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Blackout Sketch (Folder 13, Box 12)
  - Blackout Sketch (With Corn) (Folder 14, Box 12)
    Skit by Lt. D. W. Todd; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Boston (Folder 15, Box 12)
  - Brooklyn (Folder 16, Box 12)
  - Cinderella (Folder 17, Box 12)
  - Clown Production Number (Folder 18, Box 12)
    Various production numbers; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Clubcar Interlude (Folder 19, Box 12)
  - Collection of Skits and Blackouts (Folder 20, Box 12)
  - Commercials (Folder 21, Box 12)
    Skit by Lt. Frank J. Conboy; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Complaint Department (Folder 22, Box 12)
  - Courtroom Blackout (Folder 23, Box 12)
  - Crackpot Cockrell's Public Speaking Classes (Folder 24, Box 12)
    Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - The Sate Bureau (Folder 25, Box 12)
  - Day Room (Folder 26, Box 12)
  - A Day with Tojo (Folder 27, Box 12)
    Skit by Arnold M. Auerbach; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Doctor Fradler's Dilemma (Folder 28, Box 12)
  - The Doctor's Invention (Folder 29, Box 12)
  - Don't Send out Your Laundry Till the C.O. Sees Your Act (Folder 30, Box 12)
    Musical parody by Corporals Tom Adair and Joe Twerp; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Double Exposure (Folder 31, Box 12)
  - Dream Department (Folder 32, Box 12)
  - Dream Department (Folder 33, Box 12)
  - Dream On, Soldier (Folder 34, Box 12)
  - Duffy's Tavern (Folder 35, Box 12)
    By Red Graham; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Duffy's Tavern (Folder 36, Box 12)
  - Duffy's Tavern (Folder 37, Box 12)
  - The Editor (Folder 38, Box 12)